# **RAJAT SRIVASTAVA**

9910364830 Delhi

in rajatsriv19 najat19

Noida

## **EDUCATION**

## **SUMMARY**

## Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College, Ghaziabad

BTech Computer Science 2017 Graduated with 80.68% Member of Open Source R&D Team Organized Tech Events in College

Highly effective software developer offering a wealth of more than 2+ years of relevant expertise. A valuable team player who also is personable and dedicated. Seeking the chance to bring further success to an established organization through testing, deployment, and software debugging.

## **SKILLS**

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT: Node js/Koa js, PHP, Django, Laravel, Java (Basic)

DATABASE: Mysql, Postgresql, Sqlite

FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT: Vue js, Marko js, Graphiql, Jquery, Javascript, Bootstrap/Material Design

PROGRAMMING: C, C++, Java, Python

OTHER SOFTWARES/TOOLS: Git, Redis Cache, Travis CI, Mocha/Chai, Jenkins CI, Kibana, Datadog

## **EMPLOYMENT**

**PAYTM** Noida Sept. 2018 to Current Software Engineer

Working on Paytm's super cashback feature

Working on Paytm's Scratch Card Service

Working on integration of Payment Bank's pipeline with Paytm super cashback feature

Worked on random gratification for multi tiered campaigns

Worked on realtime gratification for multi-tiered campaigns Worked on localisation of apis for Paytm Ecommerce

Worked on revamping Paytm Lifafa

Worked on various functioning of Paytm Seller Panel

**SMARTPRIX WEB** Noida June 2017 to Aug. 2018 Software Developer

Implemented Search Engine Optimizations to improve search results and business flow.

Designed Node js and Vue js based admin web applications.

Developed Smartprix new website using Node js and Marko Js

Developed Smartrank, an online IDE for test purposes

Worked on Smartprix Crawler to extract data from appropriate websites

SYSBIOME TECHNOLOGIES June 2016 to July 2016 Intern

Created Samarpan project for recruitment purpose using Laravel framework

Wrote all technical documentation for new software in development.

Designed native Android mobile applications for Samarpan using Java.

**JUSTWRAVEL** Noida Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

Worked on JustWravel.com using Codelgniter framework

Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications

DR. APJ ABDUL KALAM TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY Ghaziabad Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

Web Developer (Contractual) Designed Question Paper Portal

Received letter of appreciation from university

NISANI INDIA Noida

May 2015 to Sept. 2015

Applied knowledge of JavaScript and Object-Oriented Programming to create successful designs Built Student ERP Portal website interface with HTML and CSS

## **PROJECTS**

## HACKERRANK CRAWLER

Crawl Hackerrank Solutions using command line

Book sharing web app using Python and Django

### **GEOSEARCH**

A geographical based search engine build upon Laravel Framework

Dynamic resume builder using Diango and Material Design

### TIMETABLE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Timetable management for college using Machine Learning

Options to mark attendance for faculties